我的名字叫奥利弗·奎恩
My name is Oliver Queen.
五年里  我被困在地狱一般的小岛上
After five years in hell,
我回来只有一个目标
I returned home with only one goal--
■
本字幕由ZiMuZu原创翻译
最新下载请登录www.ZiMuZu.tv
拯救我的城市
to save my city.
但我之前的方法还不够
But my old approach wasn't enough.
翻译   Michael  Liv  SophiaSaaaga
翻译   ET外星人 Silence
我得成为另一个人
I had to become someone else.
我得成为另一个存在
I had to become something else.
翻译    PiPi爱糖哥一万年
翻译   小暴徒   迷失星城
我得成为绿箭侠
I had to become the Green Arrow.
《绿箭》前情回顾
Previously, on "Arrow"...
校对   小闪迷路过[小绿箭侠]     苹果果
那你打算什么时候问那个问题
So, when are you gonna pop the question?
今晚
Tonight.
这是炼狱的地图
This is a map of Lian Yu.
时间轴风吹来的那片云  特效  咖啡Lee
我觉得它指向了瑞特在寻找的东西
I think that it leads to whatever Reiter is looking for.
要想达到目的  我需要你的帮助
To get there, I'll need your help.
后期   咖啡Lee[绿箭侠]       总监   苹果果
斯特林湾的重建项目
The restoration of Starling Bay.
别去动那块地
Leave the Bay as it is.
如果我拒绝呢
What if I refuse?
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    ustvboom
了解最新影视字幕发布信息
拯救星城的努力
The fight to save Star City
不应在阴暗中进行
isn't going to be fought in the shadows.
应该光明正大地进行
It's gonna be fought in the light of day.
我向你们保证
And I promise you
我永远不会停止努力拯救这座城市的
that I will never stop fighting to save this city.
曾经我会以为这是我的错
There was a time I would have thought this was my fault.
这不是我的错  这是我的责任
It's not my fault. It's my responsibility.
奥利
Ollie.
怎么样了
How we doing?
进行得很不错
It's actually a pretty great turnout.
谁能想到大家喜欢来捡垃圾
Who knew people would rather pick up garbage
而不是庆祝节日呢
than celebrate the holidays?
算得上不错的嬉皮式的琐碎项目  是吧
Not bad for a hippie, crunchy campaign proposal, huh?
没人喜欢听"我早就跟你说了"
Nobody likes an "I told you so."
很显然星城的人除外
Except apparently Star City.
你的支持率上升了十个点
Your approval rating is up 10 points.
我还有支持率
I have an approval rating.
是的  你有
Yes. Yes, you do.
欢迎来到政治圈  奎恩先生
Welcome to politics, Mr. Queen.
奎恩先生
Mr. Queen.
来了  失陪了
Yes. Excuse me.
今天这么多人受到你的鼓舞来这里
How do you feel about inspiring
你对此有什么看法呢
so many people to come out here today?
他们不是我鼓舞来的
Oh, I didn't inspire anyone.
这才是我认识的城市  我记忆中的样子
This is the city that I know, it's the city I remember,
这也是我们能够恢复的样子
and it's the city that we can be again.
说得好  谢谢你接受采访
Nice. Thank you for your time.
谢谢
Thank you.
说得好啊
Nice line.
你教他的吗
Wish you'd given him that one?
教了他几句吧
I might have given a note or two.
你竟然能让大家在节日期间
Well, you've got people picking up garbage
来这里捡垃圾而不是买礼物
when they should be picking up presents.
以前还真是屈才了
I think you missed your calling.
你怎么样
How are you doing?
这次过节我哥哥在我身边  奥利弗
I have my brother home with me for the holidays, Oliver.
虽然他被关着  但他就在我身边
He's in a cage, but he's here.
我们会让安迪摆脱达克的影响  约翰
We're gonna get Andy out from under Darhk's influence, John.
我向你保证
That is a promise.
如果我们能把这些垃圾中的
If we can reduce just 40% of the toxicity
细菌微生物所产生的毒性
that's produced by the bacterial micro-organisms
减少百分之四十
that have just sprung up here--
只要还原率保持下去
We can swim in just 12 more days
12天后就可以在这里游泳了
if the restitution rates stays consistent.
是的
Yes.
她就像是迷你版的你
She's like a mini you.
太可爱了  真棒
So cute. That's awesome.
大家快趴下
Everybody get down!
趴下
Get down!
跑  快跑  趴下
Go! Go, go. Get down!
我想我能远程切断无人机的电源
I think I can power the drones down remotely.
那就赶紧吧
I think now would be a good time for that.
快跑
Go!
启动
快点
Hurry!
大家快趴下
Everybody get down!
你还好吧
You all right?
绿 箭
第四季  第九集
清理星城湾
拯救星城湾
星城湾遭袭
本来是对未来充满希望的一天
A day of hope for a better tomorrow
结果却成为了星城人民绝望的一天
has turned into another day of despair for Star City.
参与帮助奥利弗·奎恩和他的竞选团队
A terrorist attack has left dozens in critical condition
清理星城湾的市民遭到了恐怖分子的袭击
after people showed up to help Oliver Queen and his campaign staff
数十人伤势严重
clean up the Star City Bay.
与此同时  星城警局和国家相关部门
In the meantime, SCPD and national authorities
正在调查这起事件的元凶
are searching for the individuals responsible,
但目前  还没有确定嫌犯
but so far, there are no suspects.
伤者有什么情况吗
Any news on the victims?
有的可以出院  有的还在做手术
Some are being released, some are still in surgery.
没死人简直是个奇迹
It's a miracle that no one died.
尽管达克已经下狠手了
Despite Darhk's best efforts.
能肯定是蜂巢干的吗
Are we sure that this was HIVE?
是的  我就是这么想的
Yeah, that's what I thought.
你还好吗
Are you OK?
当时还有孩子在场
There were kids there.
是艾利克斯
It's Alex.
他说全国的新闻台
He's saying that every news network
都想找你发表看法
in the country is looking for a comment from you.
不发表
No comment.
奥利  我们总得说点什么
Ollie, we have to give them something.
你想让我说什么
What do you want me to say?
是我让大家来帮忙的
I asked people to come and help,
可他们差点因此而丧命
they almost died because of it.
等我们有了对付达克的计划
It's-- when we have a plan to get Darhk,
我再去找媒体
then I will talk to the press.
我知道蜂巢想毁了这座城市
I know HIVE wants this city to die,
但针对志愿者活动
but going after a volunteer event,
似乎有点太过分了
it just seems a little overkill.
两周前  达克让我中止清理星城湾的计划
Two weeks ago Darhk told me to back off my plan to clean up the Bay.
今天他袭击市民
Today he went after civilians.
出于某种原因他很重视这事
This is important to him for some reason.
我们必须弄明白个中缘由
We need to understand what it is.
上一次我试图跟我哥哥谈话
Last time I tried to talk to my brother,
过程并不怎么顺利
it didn't go too well.
试着再找他谈一次
Try to talk to him again.
在笼子里待上几周会让人有所改观的
A couple of weeks in a cage will change your perspective.
相信我
Trust me.
好了  就快到了  大概还有两英里
All right, almost there. Maybe two more miles.
从何时起还有两英里就表示快到终点了
Since when does two more miles mean almost there?
泰安娜  我们得加快进程
Taiana, we need to push forward.
不  那只是你的想法
No. That's what you want.
我哥哥死了  而你让我向大海进军
My brother's dead and you have me marching to the sea.
我以为你想找瑞特复仇
I thought that you wanted to get back at Reiter.
我只想杀了那些杀害我哥哥的杂种
I want to kill the bastards who killed my brother.
康克林只是瑞特的部下
Conklin is just an extension of Reiter.
你想伤害他们
You want to hurt them,
必须让他们得不到自己想要的
you keep them from getting what they want.
你的复仇计划没有我的那么直接
Your idea of revenge is a bit more indirect than mine.
你说得对  我在利用你
You're right. I'm using you.
你说你做过潜水教练  我需要那些技能
You said you were a dive instructor. I need those skills.
但我向你保证  只要我得到想要的东西
But I'm promising you, if I get what I want,
瑞特和康克林会得到应有的惩罚
Reiter and Conklin will suffer.
瓦勒徳希望你怎么做
What would Vlad want you to do?
我的朋友们似乎认为你准备好跟我谈了
My friends seem to think you're ready to talk.
但我更了解你
But I know better.
你一直都是个固执的混蛋
You were always one stubborn son of a bitch.
卡莉和小安迪的照片
Pictures of Carly and Andy Jr.
真正的男人早该问他们的近况了
A real man would have asked for them by now.
卡莉哭了好几个月
You know Carly cried for months
因为她以为你死了
because she thought you were killed.
小安迪的成长没有父亲的陪伴
Andy Jr. grew up without a father.
而你就任由他们这样
And you let them.
不是我  是蜂巢
It wasn't me. It was HIVE.
为了让我们无法被追踪  他们伪造了死讯
They fake our deaths so we're untraceable.
弗洛伊德·罗通用蜂巢提供的弹药击中了我
Floyd Lawton shot me with ammo supplied by HIVE.
连他都不知情
He didn't even know.
但你毁了你自己的家庭  安迪
But you destroyed your family, Andy.
你从没跟他们联系过
And you never reached out to them.
一次都没有
Not even once.
你怎么这么狠心
How could you do that?
我明白  你以前不在乎  现在也一样
I get it. You didn't care then, you don't care now.
不过你要知道
Just so you know,
你的好朋友达米恩·达克
your good friend Damien Darhk
今早袭击了星城湾
attacked the Star City Bay this morning.
很多人因此受伤
Hurt a whole lot of people.
而他放在你身上的
And the neuro-blockers
那个神经阻断器已经被取出来了
he was using on you are no longer in your system.
所以从化学角度来说  你不再是他的走狗了
So chemically speaking, Andy, you're no longer his bitch.
我不是任何人的走狗
I'm not anyone's bitch.
更不是你的
And I'm not yours.
你到底怎么了  安迪
What happened to you, Andy?
如果达米恩·达克给你洗脑了
If Damien Darhk brainwashed you,
我还可以理解
I could get it.
但据达克所说
But according to Darhk,
你在斯坦贩卖毒品和武器  是吗
were you running drugs and weapons in the Stan?
我必须做我该做的事
I had to do what I had to do.
我现在给你机会  老兄
I'm giving you a chance here, man.
安迪  一个可以弥补过错的机会
A chance, Andy, to redeem yourself for all that you've done.
我必须相信在你内心深处的某个地方
I have to believe that some place deep inside of you
依然希望做出正确的选择
you want to make the right choice.
不管我爱的哥哥现在剩下什么
So I'm asking whatever's left of the brother I love,
我依然爱他  安迪
the one I still love, Andy,
我再问你最后一次
one last time, man,
达克想要星城湾做什么
what does Darhk want with the bay?
我不知道
I don't know.
妈妈
Hey, mom.
谢天谢地你没事  宝贝
Thank God you're ok, baby.
是的  我没事  我很好
Yeah, I'm ok. I'm fine.
这太可怕了
Ohh, it's so awful.
谁会在过节的时候向人群扫射呢
It's like who shoots up a bunch of people during the holidays?
就因为这才可怕吗
That's what makes it awful?
这里怎么像被圣诞老人吐过了一样
Why does it look like Santa Claus threw up in here?
是为奥利弗的竞选节日派对准备的
It's for Oliver's campaign holiday party.
我想确保你的犹太血统得到体现
I wanted to make sure your Jewish heritage was represented.
是吗  派对可能开不了了
Yeah, not so sure that's still gonna be happening.
什么  你骗人
What? Humbug.
不  那太荒唐了  宝贝
No, no, no. That's ridiculous, sweetie.
不  你们不能让恐怖分子得逞
No, you can't let the terrorists win.
我要去冲个澡
I'm gonna go take a shower.
好吧
Ok.
妈妈  你没事吧  你还好吗
Mom! Mom! Are you ok? Are you ok?
-你还好吗  -我...
- Are you ok? - I...
圣诞树灯里面的
In the Christmas lights...
戒指盒子里
in a ring box.
我找到了这个
I found this.
三克拉  公主方形  浑浊度为零
3 carats, Princess cut. No cloudiness at all.
我知道奥利弗爱你  但没想到这么爱
I knew Oliver loved you, but not this much.
他要跟你求婚
He's gonna propose.
他要求婚  老天呐
He's gonna propose. Oh, my gosh.
宝贝  不知道咱俩谁更激动了
Oh, honey, I don't know who's more excited, you or me.
谢谢你们能来
Thanks for coming.
我一直在想要怎么处理这件事
I've been trying to figure out how to deal with them.
我觉得最好还是公布事实真相
Sort of think our best bet is telling the truth.
我们只剩这一手了  老兄
It's the only play we got, man.
蜂巢让我们寡不敌众
The HIVE has us outnumbered.
如果我们要阻止达克
If we have any chance of stopping Darhk,
我们必须向全城寻求帮助
we need to ask the city for help.
如果这样做了  我们所有人
If we do this, it's going to paint a target
都会变成目标
on all of our backs.
我们自己能照顾好自己
We can take care of ourselves.
让他们曝光吧
Let's light them up.
谢谢大家赶过来  谢谢
Thank you for coming, everyone. Thank you.
今天的悲剧提醒我们
As today's tragedy has reminded us,
这是一场战争
we are at war.
这半年来  一个匿名蒙面的组织
For 6 months, we have been besieged by a nameless
一直在围攻我们
and a faceless organization
一心想要摧毁我们的城市
that seems hell bent on destroying our city.
大家称其为幽灵
You know them as the Ghosts.
其成员或许是匿名的
And while they may be anonymous,
但他们的老大却不是
their leader is not.
我们知道他的长相和名字
He has a face, he has a name,
我觉得现在是时候
and I think that it is high time
让星城市民知道此人的真实身份
the people of Star City know the truth about who he is.
他叫达米恩·达克
His name is Damien Darhk.
他代表蜂巢组织调遣幽灵
He controls the Ghosts on behalf of an organization known as HIVE.
最新美剧下载
www.ZiMuZu.tv
蜂巢希望我们的城市灭亡
HIVE wants this city to die.
现在  我会把手头唯一一张
Now, I will be distributing this,
达克先生的照片
the only known photograph of Mr. Darhk,
发给国内各大新闻媒体
to every news outlet and social media feed in the country.
重大新闻
这个人让大家好几个月不敢上街
For months, this man has made us afraid to walk the streets.
就让我们以牙还牙
I suggest that we return the favor.
我们将会开设电话热线
We will also be setting up a hotline.
单打独斗  我们或许不是达克先生的对手
Now, individually, Mr. Darhk may be able to defeat us,
但若我们团结一心  他绝无胜算
but united, he doesn't stand a chance.
祝贺你啊  达米恩  你出名了
Congratulations, Damien. You're famous.
至少也能引起他的关注
Well, that should get his attention at the very least.
电话热线交给你能行吧
You good with the hotline?
我这就去
I'm on it.
好的
All right.
祝你工作愉快
Happy hunting.
这么多节日装束
That is a whole lot of Hanukah.
是啊  为你的竞选节日派对买的
Yeah, for your campaign holiday party.
我的信仰将会表现得淋漓尽致
You better believe that my faith is going to be well represented.
费利西蒂  我们刚在一头斗牛前挥动了红旗
Felicity, ahem, we just waved a red flag in front a bull.
这不代表那头牛会径直冲过来
That doesn't mean the bull is gonna charge right away.
也不代表我们
And it doesn't mean we can
得放下手头的一切
put our entire lives on hold in the meantime.
但...帮我说句话啊  伙计
But--help me out here, man.
做不到  可不能扔完手榴弹立马躲起来
Can't do. Can't throw a grenade and then go to ground.
约翰说得对
John is right.
虽然你的演说揭露了达克
As much as your speech was about outing Darhk,
但也显示出了你的无所畏惧
it was also about sending the message that you're not afraid anymore.
要是取消你的圣诞派对...
And canceling your Christmas party--
是节日派对  节日
Holiday. Holiday.
你的节日派对
Your holiday party
传递的就是"无所畏惧"的反义词了
is sending the opposite message.
行  问问兰斯能不能再多配点安保人员
Ok. Talk to Lance, see if he can get some extra security
来这个节日派对
for this holiday party.
能问你个问题吗
Can I ask you a question?
现在吗  就在这儿吗
Now? Here?
我是说  你想问什么
I mean, what's the question?
我们做得对吗
Did we do the right thing?
达克这件事吗
You mean with Darhk?
对  他肯定会报复的
Yeah. He's gonna retaliate somewhere,
某时某地
someplace.
我们会严阵以待
When he does, we'll be ready.
我觉得瑞特让你们种毒品
I think the drugs Reiter has you and the other captives growing
只是为给一个更大的计划筹资
is just funding his bigger plan.
他在找某种秘密神器
Searching for some sort of mystical artifact.
他喜欢经文和小饰物
He likes his prayers and trinkets.
还有地图
And maps.
如果不仔细研究
But I cannot make that one
这座岛的地图  我没法找出来
without detailed survey maps of the island.
瑞特没有地图吗
Reiter doesn't have them?
我没见过
Not that I've seen.
但是我在岛上期间
But Reiter is not the first person
瑞特不是第一个来这座岛的人
to come to this island while I've been here.
如果你是来给我送圣诞礼物
If you're here to give me a Christmas present,
不管你是打算送刀
you can keep whatever knife
还是刑具  你还是留着吧
or torture device you plan on giving me.
没有礼物  至少没有那种带礼品包装的
No presents. Nothing gift-wrapped at any rate.
我只想知道你现在感觉怎么样
I just wanted to check and see how you're feeling.
我好得很
I'm great.
被达米恩·达克注视过后
Haven't wanted to snap anybody's neck
再也不想拧断对我表情不对的人的脖子了
who's given me the wrong look since Damien Darhk whammied me.
说不准我已经好了呢  老爸
I think I might be cured, Dad.
所以你觉得我要杀的那些人  恋童癖也好
So you can keep whatever file you have on a pedophile
泊车女警也好  政治家也罢
or meter maid or politician,
他们的资料你还是自己留着吧
whoever it is that you think I'm gonna kill.
自从你说了遇到达米恩·达克的情况
Since you told me about your encounter with Damien Darhk,
我就让手下去查了
I had my minions looking into it.
你最爱使唤人了
You love having minions.
达克对你的影响
Darhk's affect on you had nothing to do
跟他浸过复活泉水完全没关系
with his exposure to waters from the Lazarus Pit.
那你觉得他为什么能影响我的嗜血心性
Then why do you think he's affecting my bloodlust?
不知道
I don't know.
世上只有极少的事能使我害怕  西娅
There are very few things in this world that scare me, Thea,
我开始怀疑
but I'm beginning to suspect
我们要对付的  是使我害怕的东西
we're dealing with something that might fall into that category.
高兴点行吗  老爸  这可是圣诞节
Cheer up, Dad. Ok? It's Christmas.
我们对付的是我还不了解的
We are dealing with universal forces
神秘力量
that I don't understand yet.
请跟我保证  你会多加小心
Please promise me that you will be careful.
我跟你拉钩保证
I pinky promise.
奥利弗·奎恩
团结
你说多配点安保人员还真不是吹牛
You were not kidding about the extra security.
你从哪儿找来这么多人
Where did you find all these guys?
我有一个朋友是海豹突击队的
A friend of mine is a SEAL.
他利用他的关系网找来了这些人
He knows someone who knew someone who knew someone.
好大的关系网
Really big somebodies.
每个人都有三个我那么大
These guys are like 3 of me.
那是  劳蕾尔在哪儿
Yeah. Where's Laurel?
大概在听几百万通热线电话
Probably fielding a million calls on the hotline.
她现在一定爱死你了
She must love you right now.
我没看错吧
Is it just me
你是雇了美国军队来当侍应吗
or did you hire the US army as your caterers?
其实他们是海军
Actually, they're marines.
我是约翰·狄格尔  奎恩先生的保镖
I am John Diggle. I work security for Mr. Queen.
我是柯蒂斯·霍特  为奎恩先生的女朋友工作
Curtis Holt, I work for Mr. Queen's girlfriend.
这是我的丈夫保罗
This is my husband Paul.
好性感呢
Wow. A hottie.
真棒  柯蒂斯
Nice work, Curtis.
怎么了  我说得很奇怪吗
What, was--wait, was that weird?
有点儿
A little.
别担心  你很帅
Don't worry, you're handsome, duh,
但是你出柜了而我又几乎订婚了
but you bat for the other team and I'm practically engaged.
我说几乎订婚的意思是
And by practically engaged,
还没有订婚
I mean not engaged at all.
对吧  但是到最后什么事情都有可能发生
Right? I mean, anything can happen eventually.
可能是几年后  可能是在另一个星系里面
In like years. In another galaxy.
不好意思  能借一步说话吗
Excuse me, can I steal you for a second?
消防部部长来了
The Fire Department chief's here.
很高兴见到你  柯蒂斯
Very nice to meet you. Curtis.
你们俩结婚多久了
How long have you two been married?
至今为止五年了
5 years right about now.
原来是冬日婚礼
Oh, a winter wedding.
一定很美
It must have been beautiful.
其实是在夏天举行的
It was the summer, actually.
我们在大堡礁旁一架潜水船上结的婚
We got married on a scuba diving boat near the Great Barrier Reef.
我把戒指藏在珊瑚底的一个贝壳里面
I hid the ring in a seashell at the bottom of the reef.
你应该庆幸我能找到
And you are lucky I found it.
如果我像直男那样把它藏在甜品里的话
Well, you never would have found it
你就永远都找不到了
if I had put it in a dessert like straight people do.
你见过他吃蛋糕的样子吗
Have you seen him eat a piece of cake?
他都不咀嚼  完全是吸进去的
He doesn't chew, he inhales.
像吃蛋奶酥一样
Souffle.
费利西蒂  你还好吗
Felicity, are you ok?
我没事  我要去找我妈妈了
Yeah, just got to find my mom.
妈妈
Mom?
我永远都不能装作没看见过这个场景了
Uh, I am never gonna be able to unsee this.
对不起  宝贝
Sorry, honey.
亲爱的  给你介绍一下我的男朋友  昆汀
Um, sweetie, I would like you to meet my boyfriend, Quentin.
-她是你妈妈  -他是你男朋友
- She's your mother? - He's your boyfriend?
什么
What?
你刚刚说的是"男朋友"吗
Did you say "Boyfriend"?
不好意思  你们  你们认识
I'm sorry, do--do you guys know each other?
我以为这只是一次约会而已
I thought it was just like a date or something.
我  我  我能跟我妈妈聊聊吗
Can--can--can I talk to my mom?
就一会儿
For a second.
好的
Oh, yeah.
劳蕾尔还不知道
Listen, um, Laurel doesn't know.
是呀  我也想把自己砸晕
Yeah, I'm gonna hit myself over the head
这样我也能不知道了
with something very heavy so that I don't know either.
好吧  好吧
All right. Yeah, ok.
再见
Bye.
你不觉得昆汀很好吗
Ahh! Isn't Quentin amazing?
天呐
Oh, my gosh!
奥利弗本来想要在三个月之前向我求婚的
Oliver was gonna propose to me 3 months ago.
什么
What?
三个月之前
3 months ago.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
说来话长
It's a long story,
但是他本来要求婚的  可是之后我们搬回来了
but he was gonna propose, and then we moved back here.
那他为什么没有在你们回来
So why didn't he just pop the question
安顿好之后向你求婚呢
once you settled back in?
怎么了
Yes?
算了
Never mind.
什么  失陪一下
What? Excuse me. Hey! Hey! Hey. Hey.
发生什么事了
What's going on?
我不知道
I don't know.
是因为达克吗
Is it Darhk?
他算是原因之一吧
In as much as he's the reason
在三个月前劳蕾尔和西娅因为他而来找我们之前
that Laurel and Thea showed up on our doorstep 3 months ago
你刚好准备向我求婚
right before you were going to propose.
在你解释之前  我想跟你说
And before you say anything, you should know
我妈妈在装饰品箱子里面发现了求婚戒指
that my mom found the ring in the decorations box.
不是像你想的那样的
It's not what you think.
那就取决于
That depends on whether or not
你是不是认为我觉得你本来想要求婚
you think that I think that you were gonna propose
却又突然反悔了
and then that you changed your mind.
我没有反悔
I didn't change my mind.
还是什么变了
Well, something changed.
所有的事都变了 我们住的地方
Everything changed. Where we live,
我们做的事  我们是谁   我们...
what we do, who we are. We...
我本来想求婚的
I was gonna propose.
可是之后我们就回到了星城
But then we came back to Star City
我需要点时间去重新思考一些事
and I just needed some time to rethink things.
因为你觉得我不会答应求婚吗
Because you thought I wasn't gonna say yes?
不  因为我们做的事很危险  而我...
No, because what we're doing is dangerous. And I...
但是我选择了这种生活  我选择了你
But I chose this life and I chose you.
我不懂为什么我们不可以二者兼得
And I don't understand why we can't have both.
马贝克葡萄酒  不错
Malbec. Nice.
你怎么知道这是我最喜欢的红酒呢
How did you know that was my favorite red?
如此醇厚  又充满活力
So full bodied, so full of life.
不像你们外面的保安
Unlike your security outside.
我要澄清一下  是他们先开的枪
Oh, and in my defense, they fired first.
我猜给我的邀请函寄丢了吧
I guess my invitation was lost in the mail.
开玩笑而已
I'm only kidding.
我也不喜欢来这种场合
It's not my kind of scene anyway.
我只是想来跟我们的风云人物说两句话
Hmm. I'm only here to have a word with the man of the hour.
你想要什么
What do you want?
当然是我得不到的东西
Well, something I can't have, apparently.
你的忠诚  你的拥戴
Your loyalty, your allegiance.
我跟你说过了  如果你拒绝是要付出代价的
I told you there would be a price to pay if you refused.
是我做出的决定  不是这些人
I made that decision, not these people.
放他们走
Let them go.
我想放过他们  真心希望
Oh, I wish I could do that. I really do.
但有时教训人最好的办法
But sometimes the best way to teach someone a lesson
不是惩罚他们
isn't to punish them,
而是惩罚他们最在乎的人
it's to punish the ones he cares about the most.
再见了
Bye bye.
把他们带走
Take them.
奥利弗  奥利弗  他们把她抓走了
Oliver. Oliver, they took her.
他们把我女儿抓走了
They took my baby girl.
-拜托  -没事的
- Please. - It's ok.
没事的  没事的
It's all right. It's ok.
我会把她救回来的
I'll get her back.
他们把西娅也抓走了
They took Thea, too.
她不会有事的
All right, she's gonna be ok.
发生了什么事
What happened?
还没开始就结束了
It was all over before it started.
约翰和西娅完全没出手的机会
John and Thea, they didn't stand a chance.
我不能采取行动  否则达克会知道
And I couldn't make a move because then Darhk would know
我是站在你这边的
that I was playing for your side.
我不知道这么做对不对
And I'm not sure that was the right call.
你做得对  我们要追踪达克
You made the right call. We need to track Darhk.
你要尽力调查一切
You need to dig up everything that you can find, ok?
-马上去查  -艾利克斯
- Yeah, I'm on it. - Alex.
警察会跟你查问事情的经过
Police are gonna want to ask you about what happened.
照顾这些人  如果有需要  就送他们回家
Take care of these people. Get them home if they need it.
如果有需要  就带他们就医
Get them medical attention if they need it.
用竞选经费来支付
And pay for it out of the campaign fund.
当然  那警察呢
Of course. What about the police?
拖延警察
Stall the police.
告诉我达米恩·达克在哪
Tell me where to find Damien Darhk.
奥利弗  我们会找到他们的
Oliver, we'll find them.
连幽灵都不知道他们的下落
Not even the Ghosts know where they are.
热线有什么发现吗
Did you learn anything from the hotline?
只发现这座城里有多少疯狂或无聊的人
Only how many crazy/bored people there are in the city.
-别这么想  -想什么
- Don't go there. - Where?
你每次都这样
Your go-to place.
发生了事情以后觉得这都是你的错
Where you sit there and you say that it's all your fault.
确实是我的错  是我把达米安告知天下的
Well, it is my fault. I'm the one who outed Darhk.
我知道
I know.
我好像记得你这么做时  我们都在场
I seem to remember us all being there when you did.
我竞选市长  是因为我能保护自己
I ran for mayor because I can protect myself
我以为你们也可以
and I thought that all of you could, too.
你说得对  我们是可以
And you were right, we can.
我知道  但是你们没同意这件事
I know, but you didn't sign up for this.
奥利弗  我们可以保护自己
Oliver, we can take care of ourselves.
也包括费利西蒂
And that's including Felicity.
你鼓舞了很多人
You inspired a lot of people.
西娅  约翰和费利西蒂
Well, Thea and John and Felicity,
他们今晚需要的不是鼓舞
inspiration is not what they need tonight.
星城地方检察官
热线有发现
过来看看
我总会找到
But somewhere,
愿意跟我好好交代的幽灵
someplace there is a Ghost that's gonna talk to me.
如果没有呢
What if there isn't?
那我会使出手段让他们好好交代
I'm going to take great pleasure in trying to make them.
你准备好了吗
Are you ready?
希望吧
I hope so.
才几个小时  你怎么可能学会自由潜呢
I don't see how you can free dive after only an hour's instruction.
自从来到这个岛上
Well, since coming to this island,
我意识到我能做很多
I've learned I can do a lot of things
以前没想过的事
that I didn't think I could.
而且你是个好老师
Plus, you're a good teacher.
我可以跟你一起去
I could go with you.
那艘船我熟  很快就回来
I know the ship. I'll be back in a few minutes.
我要每个警员仔细查看所有的线索
All right, I want every uniform canvassing leads.
每位警探和我们所有的线人联系  明白吗
I want every detective talking to every CI we got. You get it?
宝贝  怎么了
Hey, baby, what's-- what's going on?
出什么事了
Something happened?
接到办公室的消息
Got a message from the office.
热线收到一条线报
A tip came through the hotline.
是吗  是有用的线索吗
Yeah? Something we can move on?
是和你有关
About you.
跟我来
Come here.
来
你在帮达米恩·达克做事吗
Are you working for Damien Darhk?
不是你想的那样
It's not what you think.
你不知道我在想什么
You don't know what I think.
达克拿你来威胁我
Darhk threatened you, ok?
我尽全力也要保证你的安全  亲爱的
I did what I had to do to keep you safe, honey.
是吗  怎么做  爸爸
Really? And what's that, Dad?
死了多少人
How many people died?
当中有多少父亲失去女儿
How many fathers' daughters?
我希望一个也没有  我
None, I hope. None, I...
我只负责打听情况
I just-- I just been eyes and ears, all right?
首先帮达克  然后上个月开始
First for Darhk, and then for the past month or so...
帮奥利弗
Oliver.
奥利弗知道这件事吗
Oliver knew about this?
知道  他发现了  一开始难以接受
Yeah, he found out. Didn't take it too well at first,
但后来他明白了
but then I think he understood.
明白什么
Understood what?
明白我会不惜一切保护我的女儿
That there was nothing I wouldn't do to protect my baby girl.
奥利弗
发来的新短信
跟我见个面
奥利弗
Oliver.
有发现吗
You got something?
只有很多会自杀的幽灵
Just a lot of suicidal Ghosts.
这对我们有什么用
Yeah, and where does that leave us?
没用
Nowhere.
老实说  奥利弗  这地方比上一个藏身处
Honestly, Oliver, this place is even easier to break into
还更容易攻破
than your last lair.
搞什么
What the hell's going--
-爸爸  -马尔科姆
- Dad! - Malcolm!
我们时间紧迫
We're pressed for time.
简单来说
Suffice it to say,
我不像大家想的那样  我还活着
I'm a little less dead than most people think.
你来这做什么
What are you doing here?
我女儿遇到危险
My daughter's in danger.
难道你不是应该先问  我怎么这么久才来
Shouldn't your first question be what took you so long?
这是什么
What is this?
蜂巢使用多相加密的卫星电话来通讯
HIVE used polyphasic-encrypted satellite phones to communicate.
这是其中一个
That is one of them.
你从哪找到的
And where did you get it?
我是拉斯·厄尔·高福
I'm Ra's al Ghul.
说不定我们可以用这个手机追踪达克
Maybe we can use the phone to track Darhk.
要是费利西蒂在的话  或许能
If Felicity were here, maybe.
但现在的情况  唯一的办法就是拿我换回他们
But as it is, our only play is trading me for them.
听着  我不会假装我弄清楚了
Ok, listen, I'm not gonna pretend to understand
现在发生的一切
what is going on here.
但是把你交给达克
But the idea of you turning yourself over to Darhk,
是我最近听过的最糟的主意
that's the worst idea I've heard in a while.
也许  但这是唯一的办法
Maybe, but it's our only play.
是我开始了这一切  就应由我来终结
I brought all this on, I have to end it.
我希望你们在这个城市待得很好
Well, I hope you're all enjoying the city.
我们有不错的交响乐
You know, we have a lovely symphony
还有西海岸最好的咖啡
and the best coffee on the western seaboard.
很好
Wonderful.
法雅德女士说你喜欢游戏  达米恩
Ms. Fayad said you like to play games, Damien.
游戏
Games?
对  游戏
Yes. Games.
如今你只是在浪费我们的时间
Now you're just wasting our time.
我们来是想看看你的创世纪进展如何
We came here to check on your progress with Genesis,
不是来看你解决个人仇怨的
not to watch you exercise a personal vendetta.
你说的是奥利弗·奎因的朋友吧
You're talking about Oliver Queen's friends.
我们担心的才不是什么市长竞选
We have greater concerns than some mayoral campaign.
市长竞选牵扯到了星城湾
That campaign's involvement in the Star City Bay
这是值得担心的
turned out to be a concern.
各位  看来事情将马上变得
Well, folks, turns out things are gonna get real interesting
很有趣了
real fast.
接到你的电话真是惊讶
I was surprised to get your call.
而且还是用我们的安全电话
And on one of our secure phones no less.
你真是深藏不露啊  奥利弗
You are more than you see, Oliver.
你应该希望你说的是错的
You really better hope that isn't true.
抓到了其最亲近的人却还敢威胁他
What's the word for a man who threatens the man
这种人是什么人
who's holding his nearest and dearest captive?
我不知道  是傻瓜吗
I don't know, idiot?
你没有杀了我的朋友  你抓他们是想表明态度
You didn't kill my friends. You took them to make a point.
你已经表明了
You've made it.
不
No.
我还没有
Not yet I haven't.
我已经来了  放了我的朋友
I'm here. Let my friends go.
真抱歉  你以为这是等价交换吗  奎因先生
I'm sorry, did you think this was quid pro quo, Mr. Queen?
我们达成了协议  快放了我的朋友
We have a deal. Now let my friends go.
有点耐心
Patience.
你知道谁完善了毒气室吗
Do you know who perfected the gas chamber?
是纳粹
The Nazis.
我困惑了好多年
For years I wondered why
为什么世界允许这种禽兽生存
the world would allow those monsters to exist,
甚至昌盛
let alone thrive.
后来我明白了  世界需要他们
And then I realized, the world needed them to.
虽然听起来很恐怖  但是每过一段时间
As horrible as it sounds, every now and then,
人类需要重置  需要重来
humanity needs a reset, a do-over.
如今时间到了
That time has come.
这是什么
What is this?
一个演示
A demonstration
一旦我们让你当上市长
of the project that you're gonna help us with
你就要帮我们完成这个计划
once we install you as mayor.
就把这个当成你朋友和家人的保险政策吧
Think of it as your friend's and family's life insurance policy.
谢谢你的服务
Thank you for your service,
你的真诚  以及你对我的信任
your mind, and your belief in me.
你将永远是蜂巢的一员
You will forever be part of our HIVE.
气室开启了
The bloom is active.
很好
Good.
顺便一提  谢谢你跑腿
And by the way, thank you for doing the legwork
清洁星城湾
on skimming the bay.
我的手下之前在港口
My people were using the harbor
培育了一种水藻
to create a certain type of algae.
它可以让我做这件事而又不被查到
One that would allow us to do this undetected.
真是失望
Bummer.
至少他比之前那个撑得久了一点
Well, at least he lasted longer than the previous one.
我想这也不错吧
I guess that's something.
好了  继续调整用量
All right, let's continue to adjust the ratio of the bloom.
你要是告诉我说总有一天
If you told me I'd ever get used to
我会习惯看你这么穿  我...
seeing you dressed up like that, I'd...
真棒  你把你的奴隶装穿出来了
Excellent. You've got your bondage outfit on.
不戴面具吗
And no mask for you?
没这爱好
Not my thing.
如果我们是去救奥利弗
If we're going after Oliver,
你带上你那些忍者朋友
wouldn't it make sense for you to bring along
不是更好吗
a few of your little ninja friends?
我不能把联盟牵扯到蜂巢里
I can't afford to pit the League against HIVE.
你找到奥利弗的位置了吗
Do you have Oliver's location?
在佩尼镇外一个废弃的工业基地
An abandoned industrial complex outside Pennytown.
你不觉得达克会
You'd think Darhk would have
检查一下他身上有没有追踪器吗
checked to see if he was tagged with a tracker.
他当然会查了  达米恩考虑非常周全
Well, I'm sure he did. Damien's very thorough.
但是奥利弗让我用
But Oliver had me tag him
一种纳米科技给他定了位
with the same particular nano technology
跟去年他给我定位的方法一样
he used on me last year.
那我呢
What about me?
不行  你会暴露你的卧底身份
No, you'll blow your cover with Darhk.
我觉得我已经暴露了
It's pretty much already blown.
能回避一下吗
Can you give us the room?
很乐意  我生活里的父女闹剧已经够多了
Happily. I have enough father/daughter drama in my life as it is.
祝你好运
Good luck.
谢谢
Thank you.
别忘了  时间紧迫
Remember, we're on a clock.
好吧  如果是关于我为达克办事之后
Ok, if this is about you not trusting me anymore
你不相信我了  那么...
after working with Darhk, then--
不  恰恰相反
No, it's just the opposite.
你做了一些事
You've done things,
可能你永远都无法原谅自己
things that you'll never forgive yourself for,
因为你要保护我
because you were protecting me.
但是应该由我来决定
But I'm the one who gets to decide
我需不需要被人保护
whether I need anyone's protection.
当父母可不是这样  宝贝
That's not how parenting works, sweetheart.
我想咱俩可以达成共识
I think that you and I can both agree
你我之间不是那么典型的父女关系
that our relationship is a little unconventional.
你戴的那面具就能说明问题
Mask should have been the first clue.
听我说  宝贝
Listen, sweetheart.
你要小心点  好吗
You just be careful out there, all right?
你要出了什么事  我真不知道该怎么办
'Cause I don't know what I'd do if anything were to happen to you.
其实不是那样  我知道我会怎么做
In fact, that's not true. I know exactly what I would do.
一定是不光彩的事
And it'd be ugly.
这些人都是志愿者吗
These people, they're volunteers?
真正的信徒  每一个都是
True believers. Every last one.
奥利弗
Oliver!
我给你们点私人空间来道别
Well, I'll give you guys some privacy to say your farewells.
约翰和西娅还好吧
Are John and Thea all right?
我想是的
Yeah, I think so.
别说你是牺牲了自己来保全我们
Please don't tell me that you traded your life for ours,
那完全是你以前鲁莽的做法
because that would be extremely old Oliver.
我只能自投罗网
I had to turn myself in.
只有这样才能知道你们被关在哪儿
It was the only way to know where you were being held.
可即使真像你们所想
One little problem. Two of you think
达克会遵守协定
that Darhk is gonna keep up his end of the bargain.
到时候金丝雀出现
But what happens when the calvary shows up
但绿箭侠没在怎么办
and the Green Arrow's not present?
达克很邪恶  他不傻
Darhk is evil, not stupid.
这都处理好了  费利西蒂
I have that handled, Felicity.
只能这么办了
It had to be this way.
为什么  因为你觉得我们处在这种境地
Why? 'Cause you think that we're in this situation
是因为你的决定吗
because of your decisions?
我非常不愿意跟你说这种话  奥利弗
Look, I really hate to be the one to break this to you, Oliver,
你不是我的上司
but you are not the boss of me.
需不需要别人的保护我自己说了算
And I am the one who decides whether I need anyone's protection.
但在那次糟透顶的圣诞派对上
But at the Christmas party from hell,
你跟我说你本打算求婚但还是放弃了
you said you were gonna propose and you didn't
因为你不确定我们的关系
because you weren't sure our relationship
是否可能在这样的生活下维持下去
could survive this kind of life.
那是节日派对
It was a holiday party.
我还有话要说的  但我们受到了袭击
And I had more to say, but we were attacked.
这就是我们  抗争
And here we are, fighting.
在艰难险阻中抗争  找寻出路
Fighting our way through the danger
而不是选择逃离
instead of running away from it.
婚姻不也是这个样子的吗
Isn't that the whole point of marriage,
度过一个个困难时期  因为我们在一起
to get through the hard times because we are together,
而不是各自为战
not in spite of it?
是啊
Yeah.
我只想让你明白  如果那时候你跟我求婚
Just so you know, if you would have asked me,
我会说我愿意
I would have said yes.
感谢你们的到来
Thank you for coming.
-我的天呐  -这是怎么回事
- Oh, my God. - What's going on?
我们说好了我自投罗网
The deal is that I bring myself here
你就放了我的朋友们
and you let my friends go.
放开我
Let me go!
真是抱歉
I'm so sorry about this.
我们有约定的
We had a deal!
如果你在脑海中回顾一下我们的对话
I think if you replay our conversation in your mind,
我们之间的协定并没有明说
our bargain was only at best implied.
即便如此  别忘了我是个坏人
Even so, bad guy, remember?
放了他们
You let them go.
我会  如果存在这个可能
I will. Existentially speaking.
你这么做  你就会失去所有对付我的筹码
You do this, you lose any leverage that you have over me.
你错了  只要他们活着
Wrong. As long as they're alive,
你就有拼搏的动力
you have something to fight for.
我要夺走你这份动力
That is what I am taking away from you.
不用担心  不会痛的
But don't worry, it's painless.
只是一定程度上
Well, mostly.
找找哪儿有缝隙
Look for seams.
这玩意可能没有百分之百密封
This place may not be 100% sealed.
我爱你
I love you.
奥利弗  不用担心  女人多的是
Oliver, don't worry, there are plenty of fish.
你要是喜欢金发女郎
If it's blondes you like,
我会叫人在20分钟内就送到你家去
I can have one at your house in 20 minutes.
送去的姑娘我不会杀的
One that I won't kill.
快过来  我们走
Hey, come on, let's go.
我还以为就这样失去你了
I thought I lost you.
我还活着  还活着
I'm here. I'm here.
这是我爸爸吗
Is that my father?
当真吗
Really?
我还以为今晚咱们打了个平手呢
And here I was ready to just call it even for the night.
你们走吧
You may go.
就像孩子们说的
As the kids say,
交给我就行
I got this.
你还真是不长记性啊
You really haven't learned anything, have you?
也不是一点都没长
I might have learned a little.
你好啊
Hi, there.
马尔科姆在哪儿
Where's Malcolm?
我迫不及待想看看面具下的那张脸
I'm dying to see what's beneath that mask.
看样子你活不了多久了
Seems like you're dying a bit, too.
我们不能把这些人都留在这里
We shouldn't leave all these guys here.
如果他们跟达克的毒气室里的人一样
If they're anything like Darhk's guy in the gas chamber,
我们就该留下他们
we probably should.
好吧  他们跟达克的毒气室里的人一样
Ok, they're definitely like Darhk's guy in the gas chamber.
你们就这点本事吗
Is that the best you've got?
四个人对抗我们这么多人
There's four of you and a lot more of us.
没错  现在有五个了
Yeah, well, now there's five.
看来你真不需要别人保护你
Guess you decided you didn't need anyone's protection.
我带帮手来了  希望你别介意
Brought the calvary. Hope you don't mind.
我们走
Let's go!
好消息
Good news.
我会让你活下去眼睁睁看我
I'm gonna let you live long enough to watch me
干掉你的绿伙伴
kill your little green buddy.
走开
Get clear.
[咒语]
Kanjigar septum...
Vohostrum.
你确定达克
Are you sure that Darhk
没在爆炸中幸存吧
didn't make it out of the explosion?
你看过恐怖片吗
Have you seen any horror movies?
这些人是打不死的蟑螂
These guys don't stay dead.
尤其是死不见尸
Especially if you can't find a body.
好悲观啊
Glass half empty much?
值得高兴的是达克在那里进行的计划
Good news is whatever Darhk had going on there,
被我们炸得一干二净
we lit it up pretty good.
梅林去哪了
Where is Merlyn?
去处理联盟的事宜了
Said he had to attend to League business.
不敢相信我会这么说
Can't believe I'm gonna say this,
我欠他个人情
but I owe him one.
我也帮了点小忙
I helped out a little bit, too.
没错
Yes, you did.
我们不是要去干点什么吗
Wait. Aren't we supposed to go to that thingy?
干点什么
What thingy?
是个惊喜
It's a surprise.
不是只有你有秘密
You're not the only one that can keep a secret.
怎么了
What happened?
遇到鲨鱼
A shark.
应该觉得我的味道不好
Guess I don't taste very good.
会留下疤
That is gonna leave a scar.
怎么了
What?
你好  泰安娜
Well, hey, Taiana.
你怎么还活生生的
You're a little less dead than you're supposed to be.
而你  可能不是间谍  但绝对是骗子
And you, you may not be a spy, but you're definitely a liar.
也就是说你骗我们说自己不是间谍
Which means you're probably lying about being a spy.
我会好好享受给你剥皮的时光
I'm gonna enjoy taking pieces out of you.
你想干什么
What do you want?
跟你谈谈
To talk.
我以为你放弃跟我谈话了
Thought you gave up on that.
本来是  但见了你的邪教领导达米恩·达克
I did, until I met your cult leader, Damien Darhk.
我们不是邪教
It's not a cult.
他底下的人  是普通人
The man has people, regular people,
老实人  我想
honest people, I'm thinking,
他们被洗脑誓死效忠他
so brainwashed they're willing to die for him.
邪教
Cult.
你想怎么想就怎么想
You know what, think what you want to think.
这是个自由的国度
It's a free country.
目前还是
For now.
这不是真正的你  安迪
This isn't you, Andy.
我认识的你
The man I knew
把我从黑暗中拉出来
pulled me out of dark waters,
当我迷失的时候  鼓励我前进
convinced me to keep going when I didn't see the point.
不  你没看见的  你看不见的
No, what you didn't see, what you failed to see
是我的真面目
is the man I really am,
一直以来  你都没发现
right in front of you the whole time.
所以我的哥哥是个幽灵
So my brother's a Ghost?
那我们就把你当幽灵对待
Fine, we'll treat you like a Ghost.
你的治安维持者越来越失控了
Your vigilante problem's getting worse.
尼克松女士  请放心
Relax, Ms. Nixon.
请专注在我们的事情上
Focus on the here and now.
我们就担心你带我们跑偏了
There's concerns that you're leading us off the rails.
不  我在带你们走向我们的目标
No, I'm leading us exactly where we need to be.
很漂亮  对吧
Beautiful, isn't it?
其实我不喜欢玉米
And I don't even like corn.
向前走  深呼吸
Go ahead, breathe.
把它吸进去
Drink it in.
告诉我你们想到了什么
Tell me what it reminds you of.
感觉很真实
Seems so real.
就像珠穆朗玛峰的空气
I liken it to the air on Everest.
也许有点稀薄
Little thin, maybe,
不过足以制造趣味
but just enough to keep things interesting.
我以为试验全部失败了
I thought the tests had failed.
上次的成功了
Not the last one.
多亏我们从星城湾改良的海藻
Thanks to the algae we engineered from Star City Bay,
这里的空气得以完美吸入
the air down here is now perfectly breathable.
我们的计划按时进行中
We are right on schedule.
现在开始第四阶段
Phase 4 begins now.
那奥利弗·奎恩呢
And what of Oliver Queen?
这全是艾利克斯的主意
This is all Alex's idea.
他要告诉市民  你没有打退堂鼓
He wanted to show the people that you're not backing down.
你只需要上去按个钮讲几句
All you got to do is, uh, flick a switch and give a speech.
就这样
That's it?
我们会在这里等你完成任务
We'll be here waiting for you when you're done.
你跟我一起来
You're coming with me.
不要
No.
天呐
Jeez.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢大家
Thank you, everyone.
这周  我们的活动被恐怖分子打断了
This week, an event just like this was interrupted by terrorists.
今晚我们聚在一起
But all of us are here tonight
向他们传达一个非常简单的信息
to send those people a very simple message.
我们不会被黑暗打败
We're not gonna let the darkness win.
我们聚集在这里一起点亮光明
So all of us are here to light a candle together.
团结
United.
因为你们  圣诞树得以点亮
This right there's possible because of all of you,
我很感谢你们
and I am grateful for each one of you.
现在我要特别感谢一个人
There is one person in particular that I am grateful for.
你
You.
在我最黑暗的时期
Someone that has stood beside me
支持我
when times were darkest.
照亮我的人生
She is the one who lights my way.
费利西蒂·斯莫克
Felicity Smoak...
你愿意让我
Would you make me
成为地球上最幸福的男人吗
the happiest man on the face of the earth?
愿意吗
Yes?
我愿意
Yes.
戴在手上看起来更大
It looks even bigger in here.
不过说实话
But to tell you the truth,
我在乎的不是钻石
I don't even care about the bling.
我只在乎你
All I care about is you.
怎么回事
What's going on?
费利西蒂
Felicity!